

Profile

Data analytics professional with a background in operations research and statistical modeling. Skills include regression modeling, design of experiments, forecasting, optimization, and discrete event simulation. Language/tool proficiencies include R, SAS, JMP, Power BI, & SQL.



Work experience

Statistical Data Analyst 05/2015 - 12/2018 Hudson Headwaters Health Network, Glens Falls, NY

Support the transition of the network from a traditional fee for service model to a value based model by identifying gaps in performance, estimating costs on a population level, and assessing risk levels for patient subpopulations. Evaluate patient outcomes of populations with different levels of interventions to determine the efficiency of such measures. Perform ad hoc statistical analyses as requested by various administrators and clinicians

Senior Resource **Management Analyst**

11/2010 - 04/2012

Express Scripts, Troy, NY

Model resources/labor needs to process pharmacy scripts in a high volume fulfillment environment. Coordinate resources/labor between the Troy, NY site and seven similar sites across the U.S. Responsible for planning and forecasting needs both at a local and enterprise level

Operations Research

06/2005 - 05/2010

Engineer

Intel Corporation, Chandler, AZ

Individual contributor to the SMS (Supply & Modeling Solutions) group in CPLG (Customer Planning & Logistics). Provided support in simulation modeling, statistics, operations research, and programming for Intel business groups. Projects included continuous improvement efforts in planning systems, forecasting, logistics, and lean manufacturing.

Teaching/Research **Assistant**

09/2003 - 01/2005

Arizona State University, Tempe, AZ

Provided database & VBA programming support for FORCe project. Taught ECE 380 (undergraduate statistics for engineers course) lab for one semester.

42 Outlook Ave, Saratoga Springs 12866, United 4803329777 k8benton@gmail.com



Education

Biometry and Statistics University of Albany (SUNY) 2015

M.S.

Industrial Engineering

2005

Arizona State University

M.S.

Industrial Engineering

2003

Arizona State University

B.S.



Skills

Languages And Tools

Visual Basic (.NET) C++ SOL JMP scripting R computing/scripting SAS (certified BASE programmer) Power BI

Modeling and Analysis

Statistical modeling and hypothesis testing Time series analysis Deterministic and stochastic optimization Computer (discrete event) simulation Regression analysis Forecasting Design of experiments



References

Available upon request